<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home-rsses on Pirate Party India</title>
    <link>https://piratepartyindia.com/home/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home-rsses on Pirate Party India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 13:05:18 +0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://piratepartyindia.com/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pirate Party of India</title>
      <link>https://piratepartyindia.com/home/foreword/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 13:05:18 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://piratepartyindia.com/home/foreword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good and responsible governance does not happen by one man alone. It is only when society rises together to change itself can we truly improve our way of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governance is not just about decisions and policies made by the current party in power.
Ask anybody you see walking in the street who his current MLA or MP is and you will understand the nature of the problem that faces our country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average Indian feels powerless to affect change in society. The policies implemented by Government should be debated beforehand in a public manner. But would there be a point to it? We cannot expect everyone to have an intimate knowledge of fiscal policy. But it is our duty to keep an eye on who the cabinet members of our elected leader are upto. An informed electorate is important to the functioning of a democracy. The Pirate Party aim to solve this by doing the research and providing easy to understand resources for people to understand the political climate of our country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need to challenge the threat of Privatization that is creeping upon us in India. we will soon find that all aspects of our lives are being controlled by private corporations who will put their profits above everything else. But how many of us can say what legislative action we support? Who do you call so that your voices may be heard in parliment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Global Pirate Party movement shares the ideals we need for our country. At the very heart of the movement is the right for every individual to share knowledge and take an equal part in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you believe as i do, in these fundamental issues. Then you might be a good fit to join our party!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educating the citizens of India&lt;/strong&gt; - It is not a college degree that i care about. People should be informed of what is going on. Informed of their responsibilites and their duties. A Government is the responsibility of it&amp;rsquo;s people, and only an informed electorate has any chance to affect change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supporting the Movement of the Pirate Party of India&lt;/strong&gt; - As a grassroots movement, we need to find our niche, find our stand on the various issues that face us.  The PPI will &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; be accepting any financial donations until our status as a party is finalized. This is a conceptual experiment to spread the vision of the PPI and that is where we would need your help. The first, foremost and as of now, the only duty of the members of the Pirate Party is to spread the word of the formation of the new party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An Indigenous self-sufficient military&lt;/strong&gt; - We need to spend more money to build indigenous factories and R&amp;amp;D centers to be more independant on our military. Apart from building the military industrial infrastructure, we must convince more and more youth to join the military. It is a core point of national crisis that nobody talks about. It is every citizen&amp;rsquo;s duty to serve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NRI&amp;rsquo;s also have a duty to their country&lt;/strong&gt; - I have been an NRI for 20 years of my life, a resident for 6 years and an NRI again for the last 2. I have lived both sides of the argument. I think that NRI&amp;rsquo;s should pay tax if it means that the country gives them a voice in chossing the government. If you ignore the NRI&amp;rsquo;s then you cannot tax them, but if you give them rights and responsibilities, taxing them for the benfit of the country seems like the right balance in this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital rights belong at the heart of politics&lt;/strong&gt; - We are in the Information Age and we should safeguard and protect the digital rights for our citizens. As the Pirate Party, we belive it should be the right of every Indian to have access to Broadband internet wherever he may be in our country. Some will say that how can you worry about internet when millions have no access to fresh water. I say solve both those problems at once, If you can provide a communal wifi station in a rural village, a communal water spot is trivial to add.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Cultural heritage need strengthening and defending&lt;/strong&gt; - We cannot ignore the masses of our nation. We must not allow intolerance against any minority and in the same breath, we cannot allow any minority to proclaim itself more important than it&amp;rsquo;s neighbour. We are all equal in the eyes of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom of speech is vital for a thriving democracy&lt;/strong&gt; - Evey Indian needs a voice and the right to be heard. This is no more than our constitution grants us. But we cannot allow the media to hijack the debate with ad and profit focused headlines. One of the party&amp;rsquo;s aims and goals would be to implement a ban of all commercialin all informational broadcast sessions whether it be Radio/TV/News/Internet. I believe advertisements removes the incentive of the media to provide balanced and informative debate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This manifesto is an experiment and a draft. A work in progress if you will. It does reflect my thoughts and opinions. I will be placing this at github to guage interest in such a party and open up the document for debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, I do require you to have github accounts to participate in any debate. I will add sections and write the manifesto little by little over the next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We seem to live in an age where politicians promise much, but all too often stand
for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no doubt what the Pirate Party stands for. We stand to break the feeling of powerlessness in politics, to truly give people their own voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wingston&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citizen, PiratePartyIndia&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>